<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/strict.dtd">
<!--
 ~ Copyright (c) 2005-2010, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
 ~
 ~ WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
 ~ Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
 ~ in compliance with the License.
 ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ~
 ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ~
 ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 ~ software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 ~ "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 ~ KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 ~ specific language governing permissions and limitations
 ~ under the License.
 -->
<html>
<head>
    <meta content="text/html; charset=ISO-8859-1" http-equiv="content-type"/>
    <title>Transport Management - User Guide</title>
    <link href="../../admin/css/documentation.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all" />
</head>

<body>

<div id="middle">
    <h1>Transport Management</h1>

    <p>
        The <strong>Transport Management</strong> page lists the available transport listeners and senders.
        From here, you can enable, disable and configure transport listeners and senders separately, without
        having to restart the server.
    </p>
    <div align="center">
        <img alt="Transport UI" src="images/trp_mgt.png" />
        <p><strong>Figure: Transport Management Home Page</strong> </p>
    </div>
    <p>
        Transport configurations are saved in the embedded registry and are loaded from there. Please note
        that WSO2 Carbon also supports the traditional axis2.xml file based transport configuration model.
        For instance you can override the transport configurations in the registry by specifying the relevant
        configurations n the [CARBON_HOME]/conf/axis2.xml file. In other words transport configuration details
        given in the axis2.xml file gets priority over the transport configuration details saved in the registry.
        Keep in mind that any changes to axis2.xml file require a server restart to take effect.
    </p>
    <p>
        HTTP and HTTPS transports are configured in the axis2.xml and thus are always loaded at the server
        startup from the axis2.xml. Also HTTP and HTTPS transports cannot be disabled since those transports
        are required by the Carbon management console and related administrative services.
    </p>
    <p>
        To enable a transport listener or a sender simply click on the corresponding <strong>Enable</strong>
        link. Then you will be taken to a page where you can specify configuration parameters for the transport
        listener or the sender you want to enable. You will notice that all the required fields are already populated
        with a set of default values. Change the default values to suit the requirements of your deployment.
    </p>
    <div align="center">
        <img alt="Transport Setup" src="images/trp_config.png" />
        <p><strong>Figure: Transport Configure Form</strong> </p>
    </div>
    <p>
        Once you specify the transport configuration details you can click on the <strong>Enable</strong> button
        on the same page to activate the transport listener or the sender. A confirmation dialog will appear and
        to enable the particular transport click <strong>Yes</strong>.
    </p>
    <div align="center">
        <img alt="Transport Enable" src="images/trp_enable.png" />
        <p><strong>Figure: Transport Enable Confirmation Dialog</strong> </p>
    </div>
    <p>
        If any of the dependencies required to enable the transport listener or the sender are missing the transport
        will not be enabled and you will be redirected back to the <strong>Transport Management</strong> page. You will
        notice that the <strong>Enable</strong> option is still available for that particular transport listener or
        sender, indicating that it hasn't been enabled. Therefore it is important that you put all the required jars in the [CARBON_HOME]/repository/components/dropins
        directory before attempting to activate a transport listener or a sender.
    </p>
    <p>
        Once enabled a given transport can be further configured or disabled. To configure a transport listener
        or a sender click on the <strong>Configure</strong> link associated with it in the <strong>Transport Management</strong>
        page. Then you will be taken to a page where you can add and edit transport parameters. Once you are
        satisfied with the configuration click on the <strong>Update</strong> button to save the changes. The
        updated settings will take effect immediately and the corresponding transport listener or sender will be
        restarted.
    </p>
    <p>
        To disable an already active transport listener or a sender use the <strong>Disable</strong> links given
        on the <strong>Transport Management</strong> page. A confirmation dialog will appear and by clicking on
        <strong>Yes</strong> button you can turn off the transport listener or the sender.
    </p>
    <div align="center">
        <img alt="Transport Enable" src="images/trp_disable.png" />
        <p><strong>Figure: Transport Disable Confirmation Dialog</strong> </p>
    </div>
    <p>
        In case of HTTP/HTTPS transport listeners and senders you will receive a warning dialog indicating that
        those transports cannot be disabled.
    </p>

    <p></p>


</div>
</body>
</html>
