<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.01 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/html4/loose.dtd">
<!--
 ~ Copyright (c) 2005-2010, WSO2 Inc. (http://www.wso2.org) All Rights Reserved.
 ~
 ~ WSO2 Inc. licenses this file to you under the Apache License,
 ~ Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this file except
 ~ in compliance with the License.
 ~ You may obtain a copy of the License at
 ~
 ~    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
 ~
 ~ Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,
 ~ software distributed under the License is distributed on an
 ~ "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
 ~ KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the
 ~ specific language governing permissions and limitations
 ~ under the License.
 -->
<html><head>
  <meta http-equiv="content-type" content="text/html; charset=iso-8859-1"></meta>
  <title>JAX-WS/JAX-RS Application - User Guide</title>
  <link href="../../admin/css/documentation.css" rel="stylesheet" type="text/css" media="all" />
</head>
<body>

<h1>Deploying JAX-WS/JAX-RS Applications</h1>

<p>WSO2 AppServer fully supports JAX-WS and JAX-RS specifications. Internally it uses <a href="http://cxf.apache.org/">Apache CXF</a>
    as the JAX-WS/JAX-RS runtime.
    If you are familiar with CXF and if you already have your CXF webapps, you can directly deploy those as
    normal Webapps in WSO2 AppServer (just like deploying on Tomcat). But in that case, you should pack all
    CXF libraries inside your WEB-INF/lib directory. </p>

<p>But if you use this feature, your CXF webapp should only contain your business logic. You don't have to
    worry about any CXF libraries and those are provided by the WSO2 Carbon OSGi environment. And also, you
    can use WSO2 Carbon Studio to easily develop your JAX-WS/JAX-RS Application. It will generate the
    needed webapp structure and you only have to concentrate about your annotations and business logic.</p>

<h2>Uploading JAX-WS/JAX-RS Applications</h2>

<p>The normal folder structure of a CXF application will be as follows. This can change depending on
    your service.</p>

    <pre>
        HellowService.war
            WEB-INF/
                web.xml
                cxf-servlet.xml
                wsdl
                lib/
                classes/
            META-INF/
    </pre>

<p><img alt="" src="images/jax-war-upload.png"/></p>

<p>Figure 1: Uploading a JAX-WS/JAX-RS archive file</p>
<ol>
  <li>In the navigator, under Manage/JAX-WS/JAX-RS, click <strong>Add
   </strong>. </li>
  <li>Click <strong>Browse</strong> to locate the file you want to
  upload. If you want to add multiple JAX-WS/JAX-RS apps at the same time, click on the
<strong>'+'</strong> sign at the right side, and new additional entry to upload a JAX-WS/JAX-RS archive
will appear each time you click. So you can select all the archives you want and deploy them at the same time.</li>
  <li>Click <strong>Upload</strong>.
    The <strong>Running JAX-WS/JAX-RS Applications</strong> page
    appears. Subsequently, if the deployment is successful, it will appear in the
    list. If the application is faulty, a Faulty JAX-WS/JAX-RS Application
    link will appear. You can click the link to view the errors.</li>
</ol>

<p><span style="font-weight: bold;">Note</span>: Instead of using this user interface, you can also manually place
    your JAX-WS/JAX-RS war file into CARBON_HOME/repository/deployment/jaxwebapps directory.</p>

</body></html>
